where my cardio lovers at NordicTrack
has been one of the leaders in cardio
equipment for a really long time and
they've stepped it up a notch with the
s22i exercise bike I've been using this
bike for a few weeks and there's a lot
to talk about from the trainer-led
classes to the automatic incline and
decline adjustments so you know the deal
let's get right to it
[Music]
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbing garage gym and for today's
video I've got the NordicTrack s22i
exercise bike in this video I'm going to
tell you everything you need to know
about this piece of equipment from the
price the features some pros some cons
and of course who should or maybe should
not buy one of these but before I get
going with all that we've reviewed a lot
of exercise bikes on barbin.com so if
you want to browse our best list just go
and search bar vend best exercise bikes
and you can find out for yourself which
ones that we like the best
foreign
okay so there's a lot to like about the
s22i but first of all I got to say thank
you to NordicTrack for the White Glove
assembly this would take a few hours to
put together so I think you should
definitely add that on as you go to
checkout the inclusion of iFit on the
monitor you know it's going to allow you
to do thousands of workouts there's 16
000 to be exact and this is obviously
you know you can do cardio workouts but
there's also strength training even yoga
classes for you to join and so this is
going to be really cool especially with
that touch screen monitor it tilts but
it also rotates 360 degrees so if you
are doing some of those other classes
that I just mentioned you can hop off
the bike and you know do so on the
ground which is really cool you have
multiple incline and decline settings so
the decline can go down to a negative 10
grade while the incline can go to a 20
grade which is really cool and this is
going to be automatically adjusted as
well as the resistance during the middle
of your workout so for example I went on
a bike ride through Washington DC the
other day and as I was riding around I
went down a slight Hill and that decline
automatically adjusted to negative one
percent and then it balanced back out
and the cool thing is they paired up
with Google Maps so you can do this
really anywhere in the world that you
want to go you know pick any City San
Francisco New York whatever you can pick
your own map take your own route you
know whatever and it's gonna
automatically adjust depending on where
you are in the world you have 24 levels
of resistance for you to work with and
it's actually relatively quiet which is
you know a good thing you know for those
early morning workouts maybe late at
night if you have roommates neighbors
you know whatever that's a really nice
touch right there the pedals are also
compatible with cycling shoes and SPD
cleats so that way you know if you have
any existing gear you know you're good
to go with this right here the ergonomic
padded seat right here can be adjusted
up and down as well as front to back
right here you have a handful of
adjustments the handlebars can also be
adjusted up and down depending on your
height and wherever you just feel
comfortable with it but I also really
enjoy just overall how the handle bars
feel you know it's got a nice texture it
feels really nice in your hands you can
also adjust you know your resistance and
your incline or decline manually as well
you do have some handles right here with
some buttons to do that on your own the
push to stop is a really nice safety
feature you know if you're whatever
reason you need to stop just simply
press that down and it's going to stop
for you there's a built-in fan you know
meant to cool you off which is really
nice you also have two water bottle
holders right here there's even a tray
up top for your phone to go
nordictrack's even going to toss in two
three pound dumbbells for you to use
there's Bluetooth capabilities for your
headphones or maybe an external speaker
you can hook up a heart rate monitor as
well if you want to and there's even
popular music loaded on there as well so
there's no type of you know random
instrumental music there's actual
current up-to-date music that's loaded
onto the monitor that way you have
something entertaining to listen to
foreign
things about the s22i but there's still
a few things you might run into that you
might not be too crazy about or you know
it might just be a little bit of a
hassle so let's talk about the available
space this is a relatively big exercise
bike you know some people might not have
enough space to you know house this so
definitely be cautious with that it's
also pretty expensive it's priced right
around 1900 bucks and you know that
might just fall out of some people's
budgets as well so definitely you know
keep that in mind and not everybody is
going to be crazy about you know
streaming the classes not everybody
really cares for that now I personally
think that's how this was meant to be
used even though you can you know create
your own workouts you don't have to join
something but you know if you're not
crazy about that you don't really care
for you know all those added features
it's probably gonna be better off with a
more you know basic exercise bike you
also need to have pretty solid Wi-Fi
connection and that's because of how
many workouts and everything that are
loaded onto the monitor but you know
just keep that in mind I'm obviously in
a garage away from the house not really
you know too close to the router but
sometimes it can still take a while to
load to buffer sometimes the quality of
the graphics you know it takes a while
for it to really catch up and give you
that HD picture you know that it's meant
to do and you also have a set of wheels
on the front it's going to help you out
a lot in terms of portability but
there's not really a designated handle
right here for you to you know grab I
usually just reach down here at the
bottom and lift it up from there but you
know because of that lack of a handle it
might be a little tricky sometimes as
you go to move it about your personal
space so with your purchase you're also
going to get a free month of iFit but
after that month you're gonna have to
pay about 40 bucks a month just to gain
access to the available classes you
don't have to purchase iFit you know you
can do your own manual workouts on here
but I personally think that's you know
how this was meant to be used so you
know it's definitely something worth
remembering but if you don't care for
all that you're probably just going to
be better off going after a more basic
exercise bike foreign
[Music]
for the NordicTrack s22i exercise bike
this bike is available for right around
1900 bucks that's obviously not cheap
now the NordicTrack does have a couple
options that are cheaper than this one
right here but the overall setup you
know the feel everything with those
bikes are just overall you know very
different than this one right here and
you know aside from the other bike they
have that's more expensive than this one
this is one of the most expensive
options on the market so you know unless
you really want you know those
trainer-led classes all those luxury
features that this bike offers you know
including those automatic incline
Decline and resistance adjustments you
might be better off going down the
old-fashioned route of you know a fan
bike or really just anything more basic
and save that money if you're just
looking to burn some extra calories now
NordicTrack is going to allow you to
finance this purchase if you don't want
to spend all that money up front but
this is going to vary a little bit you
know depending on if you want the
extended warranty or maintenance package
since you know if you add some of that
on you could be spending around 2 300
bucks but if you go for that regular you
know Nineteen Hundred Dollar package you
can make monthly payments of about 49
bucks a month for 39 months
okay so let's talk about the available
classes that are loaded onto your
monitor from iFit so like I said there's
over 16
000 different classes for you to join
obviously you know you can do your
cardio stuff you can also do strength
training yoga meditation there's a
there's a whole lot for you to work with
right there but let's talk about the
cycling experience so you have different
options you know there's Studio
experiences and there's Global workouts
as well so both of these are exactly you
know how they Sound Studio classes
mimicking being in an actual studio in a
spin class with a personal trainer and
you know fellow workout people that are
joining that as well now with the global
classes it literally allows you to
travel the world which is really cool
you know you're going to be learning
about different cultures and different
aspects of you know whatever region
you're deciding to go to which is
honestly really cool because it can
distract you from that intense workout
and it definitely makes the time go a
whole lot faster I also think it's
really cool how the resistance as well
as the incline and and decline settings
are all going to be automatically
adjusted in real time you know depending
on the course or workout you know that
you're deciding to do so I already
referenced my ride through DC the other
day and how it went down to negative one
percent but let's say you wanted to go
on a ride you know in the mountains or
you know in the hills and you're going
on these on this terrain and you're
going up and down you can expect you
know all of that to be automatically
adjusted for you as well now once again
you know I did reference the fact that
not only can you do the cardio classes
but their strength training and yoga
classes available but this is all
available through the iFit compatible
app which brings me to my next point so
obviously you know you have all these
cardio classes you can do with your bike
but with that iFit membership you know
you gain access to strength training
yoga and even meditation classes which
really makes that worth it in my opinion
and you know with the addition of that
companion app you can stream all of
those other workouts directly from your
phone okay so let's expand on that
companion app now so so I think this is
a really great tool obviously you can
stream those extra classes like the
strength training and yoga you know
anything that doesn't require your bike
that's really cool but this is also a
really great way to track all of your
stats so you can track everything over
the past week month year to date even
years past if you choose to do so now
there's also a calendar tab it's going
to show you all your recently completed
workouts there's a trophy case tab it's
going to show you all the completed
challenges that you've done but if you
haven't done any don't worry you can
click on Discover and it's going to show
you a bunch of different challenges for
you to select from
[Music]
okay so obviously this is a really
high-tech piece of equipment so why
don't we spend some time talking about
that technology so let's talk about that
monitor first it's a 22 inch touchscreen
display it rotates 360 degrees but it's
also going to tilt forward back you know
whatever you're comfortable with it can
do it which is really cool you have two
30 watt speakers underneath that monitor
and all of nordictrack's equipment uses
Google Maps which is a really nice touch
you can pick really any city in the
world you want to go to and you can
follow along with the Google Maps street
view and kind of mimic you know riding
around town you have Bluetooth
capabilities you know that way you can
pair up your phone headphones heart rate
monitor you know even an external
Bluetooth speaker if you want all your
noise coming out of that so that's
pretty cool you have 24 levels of
resistance and all this stuff's going to
be automatically adjusted with that auto
adjust technology which I think is
really cool it's including your incline
and your decline overall this whole bike
is relatively quiet I mean obviously
it's going to make some a noise it has
to as it adjusts the incline and the
decline but for the most part it's
pretty quiet which is you know a really
nice touch it also operates on Android 9
OS technology and you cannot forget
about that built-in fan as you start to
work up a sweat
[Music]
let's break down the build and some of
the features now with the s22i you have
a steel framework right here it feels
really durable really sturdy but
obviously that 22 inch touchscreen
monitor right there it's you know made
of glass on the front so you definitely
want to be careful you don't want to
break that and it kind of ruins the
whole experience right so this bike is
about 58 inches tall around 60 or 61
inches long and about 22 inches wide it
weighs 205 pounds which is pretty hefty
so thankfully you do have those Wheels
on the front it's going to make it
portable and it has a 350 pound weight
limit which is a really high number for
a stationary bike and I really like the
fact that NordicTrack does toss in that
10-year warranty on the frame the pedals
are compatible with SPD cleats and
cycling shoes so all of my dedicated
cyclists you're really going to like
that right there I really love the fact
that you have the automatic resistance
incline and decline adjustments that
will happen for you but on the
handlebars there's also your manual
adjustments you you can use those as
well and also underneath the actual
framework of this bike you're going to
notice there's these feet that help
stabilize the bike itself but if you
ever notice your bike is a little wobbly
for whatever reason just lift up the
bike and then you can actually Twist on
those feet and extend them and it's
going to you know help stable that bike
even more
[Music]
okay so let's go ahead and break down
the s22i up close for you guys and also
just want to show you how to use
everything properly so first of all you
definitely need a three prong outlet to
power this bike it's a relatively long
cord which is really nice but you
definitely need a three prong outlet
that cord is going to plug in down here
underneath the pedals you also have an
on off switch and it's recommended that
after every use you flip it off and you
unplug the bike just to avoid any type
of power surge issue it's definitely
something that you don't want while I
got you down here let's go ahead and
talk about this little motor right here
this is for your incline and decline
adjustments as you can see right here
now it's obviously going to make some
noise it has to but the grand scheme of
things it's really not that loud it's
definitely something that you know you
can get used to let's talk about the
seat as I mentioned you do have
adjustments you know you can do
horizontal adjustments to do that you
untwist on that knob right there and
then you're free to slide this around
and it's just really simple to do and
the same goes for the height and just
twist on that knob and then you can pull
up you can slide it down really whatever
is comfortable for you you can do it
overall this seat is you know it's
obviously padded it's it's comfortable
it's pretty much a normal you know bike
seat now let's transition to these
pedals right here once again these are
compatible with SPD cleats and cycling
shoes but you know if you don't have
those you can take this little holder
right here I guess you could call it you
can unscrew that and take that out if
you don't necessarily want it there
which is kind of cool now let's move a
little further up you do have your push
to stop right here if you ever need to
stop in a you know a split second you
can definitely do so just you know push
down on that it's going to stop
everything for you you do have your two
water bottle holders right here which is
really nice and let's talk about these
handles I really like the feel of them
right here this texture grip it just
feels really good in your hands and I
also really like how you know you can
definitely do your incline decline in
your resistance adjustments manually you
know if you ever want to if you know
you're on one of those classes and you
you know that incline is a little too
hard you can definitely bring it down a
notch if you want to now you also have
two three pound dumbbells right here for
you to use and also like this little
phone tray right here you know it fits
perfectly and it's not gonna you know
fall out or you know slide around or
anything you can also adjust the
handlebars as well to your comfort level
you have six different adjustments and
it's the same process as with the seat
you just untwist on this knob right here
and then you're free to move it down
move it up really whatever you want to
do now underneath this monitor you have
your two 30 watt speakers you have your
volume control buttons as well as your
fan control buttons your fans you know
located right here in the middle and
that definitely is helpful and as you're
deep into a workout you're sweating
you're hot that comes in handy now let's
talk about this monitor But first you
know that's a camera and that camera
doesn't serve any purpose right now I'm
sure you know eventually NordicTrack is
going to include that in some way shape
or form term so I'm thinking they're
just trying to get ahead of the game and
it's going to go ahead and include this
on all their monitors now let's go ahead
and get going you know once again this
is touch screen tap to start there's a
lot for you to do so right here it's
going to show you your past seven days
you know what you've done you can adjust
that though you past 30 days your year
to date all that good stuff you know
it's gonna also this is also compatible
with all NordicTrack equipment so
treadmill bike rower elliptical strength
like all that stuff it's all going to
pop up right here
you can scroll on the home page and
check out the featured classes the
latest from iFit you'll see some of
these new challenges they have up next
for you a bunch of other challenges
recommended you can Browse by category
you know beginner Road Mountain active
recovery I mean there's a lot right here
for you to do there's even TED talks on
here which is pretty cool now if you've
got a calendar it's going to show you
your most recently completed workouts
that you've done mine's updating my time
zone for some reason right now don't
know why but you know a bunch of
different workouts that I've done lately
are right here you can go to your create
right here and this is really cool so
this is listed at Central Park New York
right now but you can type in anywhere
in the world that you want and it's
going to show you a map and you can
literally pick anywhere and you can
create your own course your own route
which is a really cool thing right there
and it's also going to show you you know
the street level view or satellite like
we have it right now now if you go to
browse
you know it's obviously you know for you
to browse everything it's going to have
the library full of these workouts right
here this is what I was talking about
earlier sometimes it takes a while to
load but that's also because I'm you
know a pretty good distance away from my
router there's just a lot on here now as
we browse through right here there's
those challenges again iFit 101 you can
also categorize your workouts you know
less than 20 minutes Beach City forests
landmarks mountains I mean there's a lot
of different options right here for you
to choose from and you know there's more
you know quick rides quick stress
there's yoga I was talking about there's
some strength training classes right
here meditation
there there's so many things right here
you're gonna
run out of time trying to find one than
you will before you run out of uh
options to choose from now if you go to
trophy case that's what I was talking
about
it's going to show you any challenges
you completed I'm not done with my fit
for fall yet but I am in the middle of
it so once I'm done with that that badge
is going to be right there I haven't
done any Live Events yet and really
don't have too many Milestones done but
that is going to pop up right there and
you can also click on Discover right
here
and it's going to show you a bunch of
challenges that you can sign up for all
right so now the only thing left to do
is to hop on this bad boy just kind of
show you guys how things are done so I
talked about how you can create your own
you can go to any City basically in the
world with Google Maps there's also a
manual start which is really cool just
click up on that top right corner from
the home screen
it's going to start loading for you and
before every single workout you're going
to have a warm-up so it's going to be
really cool you know you obviously you
want to get warm before you start
cycling too hard and heavy right but you
know as you're in the workout it's also
going to show your incline your Watts
time elapsing all that stuff but you can
there's so many things right here
vertical loss it also showed vertical
gain a second ago
that this would cycle through that's
just all your Watts right there
estimated calories burned and calories
burned an hour time elapsed you know
distance Cadence there's so many
different things right here so we're
going to go ahead and end the warm-up
we're good to go I've already warmed up
and so basically this is showing a bit
of a track you know so quarter mile
quarter mile track length and basically
you know I'm good to go we can just go
ahead and start pedaling cool thing is
you know my resistance right now is at
one if you want to adjust this on your
own which right now we're going to just
press up on Resistance and it's going to
slowly become harder for you
and also here I'll go ahead and bring
this back down for a second just to show
you how you can simply do both you can
also do the incline and decline so let's
start with the incline
it's going to go up as a half percent
every single time I'll just hold it down
to give you a good view
I feel like E.T right now on his bike
and then yeah we're right now up at 20
incline the resistance is also harder
even though it says it's at four it's
definitely harder than that and it feels
harder than if this incline was at zero
so let's go and drop it right back on
down
and this resistance is obviously getting
easier now
as we go all the way down to negative 10
right there I mean this is about as easy
as it gets so you know that's obviously
you know going to be true to life and
you know true to how and you know
negative 10 decline would be but if you
want you could also still increase that
resistance a little bit and I don't
really notice much of a difference but
you might at home we just went ahead and
finished that workout obviously you know
I didn't do a full one but it's still
going to show your stats and this is
with every single workout once you're
done it's going to show you your time
your distance estimated calorie burn and
that's going to be you know more
accurate if you were to pair up a heart
rate monitor with your device right here
also it's just going to show everything
right here inclined percentage and if
you were in an actual class with other
people it also have a leaderboard
function right there and this is based
off of you know everything you're doing
over time it's going to give you a
higher score all right and lastly I want
to go back to the home page really fast
so if you click on this top left corner
it's going to pull down this menu bar
it shows your account other accounts you
can invite users you can have up to four
different people on your account which
is really cool you know you can split
that membership you could split the bike
with somebody if you wanted to which is
you know a really nice thing because you
know it is about nineteen hundred
dollars now
we go back over here you do have your
Bluetooth accessories your Wi-Fi
settings you can change the appearance
so right now we have it in light mode
you put it in dark mode if you want to
so I just did a reset you know as I said
you can invite users right here but
we're just going to click on my name
really fast and as you see you know it's
in that dark mode so some people might
like that might be a little bit easier
on your eyes but let's go back over here
to this menu you can this is where you
do your Bluetooth accessory so if you
have anything right here you know your
headphones heart rate straps you know
whatever just make sure it's in pairing
mode that's going to pop up right here
and it's really easy to connect
everything it's not that bad I promise
and then lastly you know say you do have
another profile on here you can switch
that profile really quick right there
with that button but if you click on my
account it's going to pull up all of
your personal information that you put
in to begin with so we can edit this as
well
click on that edit button and there's
all these questions it's going to ask
you you know gender height current
weight it's also going to ask you your
workout type you know if you like
endurance you know cross training active
recovery what type of goals you have
such as you know improving overall
health and wellness workout days your
activity level your workout duration and
even what type of equipment that you
like to work out with and you can change
this at any given time so I have
dumbbells listed right there but you can
also do kettlebells resistance bands
exercise ball all that all that good
stuff right there Simply Save it you can
go back and edit this whenever you want
to just save that again and your profile
is going to be safe that way
foreign
so let's talk about the people who might
want to purchase this bike well if you
do in fact need that extra motivation
that a personal trainer can provide but
you know you don't want to go to a
studio for cycling class I think you're
really going to like the inclusion of
iFit with the monitor right here because
it's a loaded full of classes also you
know the automatic adjustments with the
resistance incline and decline is going
to be great for anybody who doesn't know
the optimal weight you know use this
type of technology and if you are a
dedicated cyclist I think you're also
really going to love the fact that your
existing SPD cleats or cycling shoes are
going to be compatible with these pedals
now when it comes to those who might not
want to purchase this bike it really
just boils down to three things and
first of all is the money right so this
bike is right around 1900 bucks that's
obviously pretty expensive now it's
expensive for a good reason you know
it's a luxury item but not everybody you
know wants to spend that much money on
an exercise bike which kind of leads me
to my next point you know some of y'all
don't want to spend that money also
don't really necessarily care about
those instructor-led classes so if that
is the case you know if that's you I'd
suggest going after a more standard
exercise bike that doesn't have those
extra you know luxury features and
lastly is space now the actual framework
of this bike really isn't you know two
terribly big but you know with the
addition of that monitor you know it's
what makes it a little bit wider so if
you don't have enough space for this
bike I'd suggest trying to find a
smaller option that's all I have for you
guys today on the NordicTrack s22i
exercise bike it's a really high-tech
stationary bike I really like the fact
that you have the automatic adjustments
with your resistance incline and Decline
and I actually thoroughly enjoy the
instructor-led classes that are on that
touch screen monitor this is a pretty
expensive product though so it might be
better suited for people who really want
those luxury features thanks for
watching everybody I hope this video was
really helpful that I was able to break
down everything there is to know about
this exercise bike as always stay posted
for my next video but for now you should
definitely head over to barbin.com to
read more about this product all you got
to do is search bar Bend NordicTrack
s22i exercise bike review you'll find
all the details and everything that I
discussed here today now I'm gonna go
get my workout in I'll catch y'all next
time
[Music]
thank you